<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Behavioral InfoSec on Kelly Shortridge</title>
    <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/tags/behavioral-infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Behavioral InfoSec on Kelly Shortridge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 20:58:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swagitda.com/blog/tags/behavioral-infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware: Towards an Economic Equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/ransomware-towards-an-economic-equilibrium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 20:58:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/ransomware-towards-an-economic-equilibrium/</guid>
      <description>This post will explore my thoughts on how the economics of physical ransom translate to digital ransom, and how we as an industry might want to reconceive our current approaches to considering and dealing with ransomware – and the criminals who run ransomware campaigns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Prospect Theory Meets Chaos Engineering</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/when-prospect-theory-meets-chaos-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/when-prospect-theory-meets-chaos-engineering/</guid>
      <description>There is a connection between my research into behavioral models of information security and my Black Hat USA talk with Dr. Forsgren from last week regarding DevOps and the future of information security that might not be immediately obvious. However, it is a connection I believe is worth illuminating.
Adopting the “chaotic infosec” philosophy (the application of chaos engineering to information security) can influence those who build and secure systems to operate more like attackers – that is, to be more risk averse and to more quickly update their mental models given new inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choice Architecture for InfoSec Blue Teams</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/choice-architecture-infosec-blue-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2017 16:17:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/choice-architecture-infosec-blue-teams/</guid>
      <description>I recently spoke at Art into Science: A Conference for Defense, which was an intellectually-stimulating (and delightfully quirky) conference focused on moving towards a professional discipline for defensive infosec. Sadly, I had to rush through the last part of my presentation, so I wanted to do it justice by fleshing out my thoughts here. I’m going to skip through the first two sections of my talk— an introduction to cognitive biases and how they manifest in infosec, then challenges that arise due to the group nature of blue teams — but feel free to check out the slides here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behavioral Models of InfoSec: Prospect Theory</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/behavioral-models-infosec-prospect-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2016 20:20:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/behavioral-models-infosec-prospect-theory/</guid>
      <description>To those in the information security / cyber security industry, it’s an accepted truth that there exists a pernicious incentive structure that overwhelmingly puts the odds in the attacker’s favor. The consistent narrative is that defenders make irrational decisions and focus on the wrong problems while vendors peddle FUD and snake oil that not just fails to bolster the defensive cause, but inflicts ongoing harm.
But, I’ve seen less in the way of seeking to understand defenders’ irrational decision making patterns and why the industry is the way it currently is…and even less about how to fix this toxic feedback loop.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>