<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>InfoSec on Kelly Shortridge</title>
    <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/tags/infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in InfoSec on Kelly Shortridge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:00:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swagitda.com/blog/tags/infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience in Security 101</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/resilience-in-security-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/resilience-in-security-101/</guid>
      <description>A short primer on what resilience means in information security, intended as a resilience 101 resource for people who build, maintain, and secure systems or lead teams who do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kelly&#39;s Hierarchy of Security Product Needs &amp; Vendor Selection v1.0</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/kellys-hierarchy-of-security-product-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 07:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/kellys-hierarchy-of-security-product-needs/</guid>
      <description>A look at the infosec industry&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy of product needs and what drives vendor selection. #antisec</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shall We Play a Coordination Game?</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/shall-we-play-a-coordination-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 20:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/shall-we-play-a-coordination-game/</guid>
      <description>Examining the relationship between enterprise security and DevOps teams through the lens of game theory, specifically coordinative games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2020 RSA Innovation Sandbox Finalists</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2020-rsa-innovation-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 21:33:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2020-rsa-innovation-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>How do the nominees for the 2020 RSA Conference’s Innovation Sandbox look compared to prior years? I decided to explore the funding profile of the 10 selected startups for the competition, but with the benefit of comparison this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware: Towards an Economic Equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/ransomware-towards-an-economic-equilibrium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 20:58:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/ransomware-towards-an-economic-equilibrium/</guid>
      <description>This post will explore my thoughts on how the economics of physical ransom translate to digital ransom, and how we as an industry might want to reconceive our current approaches to considering and dealing with ransomware – and the criminals who run ransomware campaigns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Prospect Theory Meets Chaos Engineering</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/when-prospect-theory-meets-chaos-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/when-prospect-theory-meets-chaos-engineering/</guid>
      <description>There is a connection between my research into behavioral models of information security and my Black Hat USA talk with Dr. Forsgren from last week regarding DevOps and the future of information security that might not be immediately obvious. However, it is a connection I believe is worth illuminating.
Adopting the “chaotic infosec” philosophy (the application of chaos engineering to information security) can influence those who build and secure systems to operate more like attackers – that is, to be more risk averse and to more quickly update their mental models given new inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Black Hat USA 2019 Business Hall</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:35:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2019/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisite plug that you should come see my talk with Dr. Nicole Forsgren at Black Hat next week (16:00 in South Pacific)!
What type of vendors are showing themselves off in the Business Hall? Are they mostly startups? Exactly like last year, 46% of the vendors in the Business Hall are startups backed by venture capital (VC) firms. Private companies represent only 13% of total vendors this year (vs. 17% last year), and there are far more acquired companies (&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darth Jar Jar: a Model for Infosec Innovation</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/darth-jar-jar-model-infosec-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 08:30:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/darth-jar-jar-model-infosec-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Despite its seeming absurdity and superficiality, the theory of Darth Jar Jar can serve as a poignant parable for security innovation. For those unfamiliar, the notion of a Darth Jar Jar springs from a meticulously researched fan theory from the Star Wars subreddit. While I do not wish to spoil the breathtaking beauty of the fleshed-out theory, the underlying legend is one of an ostensibly bumbling fool who, in reality, is an insidious puppet master full of cunning and strength.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reflections on the 2019 RSA Conference</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/my-reflections-on-rsac-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 21:28:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/my-reflections-on-rsac-2019/</guid>
      <description>Artist’s rendition of how I felt by Thursday morning of the con
Reflecting on my existential crisis during RSAC, I tried to distill what exactly was so troublesome about the conference. The expo floor was less two separate halls, as per years prior, and more like Mordor, with a befouled sprawl connecting Minas Morgul and the Black Gate — but instead of orcs and Uruk-hai, vendors crammed the hallways that used to serve as open breathing space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfoSec Startup Buzzword Bingo: 2019 Edition</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/infosec-buzzword-bingo-2019-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 16:57:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/infosec-buzzword-bingo-2019-edition/</guid>
      <description>This is the third edition of my Infosec Buzzword Bingo, just in time for 2019’s RSA Conference (RSAC). Rather than relying on my keenly tuned snake oil spidey senses to generate the words populating the bingo card, I took a more data-driven approach this year.
I surveyed 100 companies’ websites[1], the vast majority of which are exhibiting at RSAC and possess VC funding. I did not include any of the large security vendors[2], who probably could populate their own bingo cards across their mastodonian websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2019 RSA Innovation Sandbox Finalists</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2019-rsa-innovation-sandbox-finalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 19:02:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2019-rsa-innovation-sandbox-finalists/</guid>
      <description>This year’s nominees for the 2019 edition of the RSA Conference’s Innovation Sandbox were announced this morning. As I’m wont to do, I wanted to explore the funding side of these ten startups.
Total Funding Raised &amp;amp; the Latest Stage for each 2019 RSA Innovation Sandbox Finalist ($USD millions)
The median funding raised by all ten startups is $10.5 million (mean of $10.3 million), which makes sense for an early stage-flavored competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cyber Tub: Communicating the Dynamics of Information Security Risk Management</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/the-cyber-tub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Dec 2018 22:02:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/the-cyber-tub/</guid>
      <description>This is probably how a Cyber Tub looks, right?
People struggle to understand how risk accumulates in complex systems, thereby also not understanding the extent to which risk must be reduced. This misapprehension can lead to “wait and see” decisions that cause a problem to snowball, or mitigations that don’t meaningfully reduce risk, creating the feeling of just barely treading water in your security program.
It is challenging for people to understand risk dynamics conceptually for two primary reasons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Cyber Security Predictions</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/2019-cyber-security-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 20:07:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/2019-cyber-security-predictions/</guid>
      <description>Fed up with ridiculous infosec predictions for the upcoming year, I decided to aggregate them all and use the power of Markov Chains to generate my own list. What follows is the result, very lightly edited solely for readability. You can see last year’s edition here.
In 2019, we predict 2019. Cyber espionage, cybercriminals — in 2019, they materialize. What if this is a dangerous reality? For example, consider how the world feels sometimes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Black Hat USA 2018 Business Hall</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 18:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2018/</guid>
      <description>What type of vendors are showing themselves off in the Business Hall? Are they mostly startups? Not quite “mostly,” but 46% of vendors in the hall are indeed VC-backed companies at varying stages of maturity. Privately held companies are a non-trivial segment at 17%, and there are 30 Private Equity-owned companies making up 12% of the hall. There are also 12 companies who are acquisitions, primarily those who were acquired within the past year; booths require being booked far in advance, leaving insufficient time to be assimilated into their acquiror’s booth (if so desired).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Red Pill of Resilience in InfoSec</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/red-pill-of-resilience-infosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 17:26:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/red-pill-of-resilience-infosec/</guid>
      <description>What follows is the full text of my keynote, also available as a video and as slides.
 There has been insufficient exploration of the first principles of resilience in the context of information security, despite the term being superficially peppered in our common discourse. Too often, resilience is conflated with robustness — to the detriment of us all.
To state more poetically, through the pen of the notable fantasy author Robert Jordan referencing one of Aesop’s fables, “The oak fought the wind and was broken, the willow bent when it must and survived.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>