<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>InfoSec on Kelly Shortridge</title>
    <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/tags/infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in InfoSec on Kelly Shortridge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 08:30:26 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://swagitda.com/blog/tags/infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Markets DGAF About Cybersecurity</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/markets-dgaf-about-cybersecurity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 08:30:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/markets-dgaf-about-cybersecurity/</guid>
      <description>Do public markets actually care about cybersecurity? The evidence suggests no.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deciduous: A Security Decision Tree Generator</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/deciduous-attack-tree-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 08:00:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/deciduous-attack-tree-app/</guid>
      <description>Introducing Deciduous, a web app that lets you generate security decision trees (aka attack trees) with minimal effort.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Cybersecurity Predictions, as told by a bot</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/2021-cyber-security-predictions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jun 2021 10:38:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/2021-cyber-security-predictions/</guid>
      <description>I forced a bot to read over 1,000 cybersecurity predictions and then asked it to write its own cybersecurity predictions for 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Security Decision Trees With Graphviz</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/security-decision-trees-with-graphviz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 08:00:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/security-decision-trees-with-graphviz/</guid>
      <description>This post walks through creating a decision tree for pragmatic threat modeling using the open source graph vizualization tool Graphviz (with an AWS S3 bucket containing sensitive data as an example).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On YOLOsec and FOMOsec</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/on-yolosec-and-fomosec/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Sep 2020 08:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/on-yolosec-and-fomosec/</guid>
      <description>This post will explore why both YOLO security (YOLOsec) and FOMO security (FOMOsec) are pernicious disservices to infosec defense and how you can spot them so that you may yeet them from your organization’s security strategy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Infosec Buzzword Bingo: All Editions</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/buzzword-bingo-all-editions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Aug 2020 12:47:37 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/buzzword-bingo-all-editions/</guid>
      <description>Every edition of Infosec Startup Buzzword Bingo thus far (2017 through 2020).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resilience in Security 101</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/resilience-in-security-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 20:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/resilience-in-security-101/</guid>
      <description>A short primer on what resilience means in information security, intended as a resilience 101 resource for people who build, maintain, and secure systems or lead teams who do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kelly&#39;s Hierarchy of Security Product Needs &amp; Vendor Selection v1.0</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/kellys-hierarchy-of-security-product-needs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 2020 07:57:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/kellys-hierarchy-of-security-product-needs/</guid>
      <description>A look at the infosec industry&amp;rsquo;s hierarchy of product needs and what drives vendor selection. #antisec</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shall We Play a Coordination Game?</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/shall-we-play-a-coordination-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2020 20:22:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/shall-we-play-a-coordination-game/</guid>
      <description>Examining the relationship between enterprise security and DevOps teams through the lens of game theory, specifically coordinative games.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2020 RSA Innovation Sandbox Finalists</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2020-rsa-innovation-sandbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2020 21:33:26 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2020-rsa-innovation-sandbox/</guid>
      <description>How do the nominees for the 2020 RSA Conference’s Innovation Sandbox look compared to prior years? I decided to explore the funding profile of the 10 selected startups for the competition, but with the benefit of comparison this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ransomware: Towards an Economic Equilibrium</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/ransomware-towards-an-economic-equilibrium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 20:58:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/ransomware-towards-an-economic-equilibrium/</guid>
      <description>This post will explore my thoughts on how the economics of physical ransom translate to digital ransom, and how we as an industry might want to reconceive our current approaches to considering and dealing with ransomware – and the criminals who run ransomware campaigns.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Prospect Theory Meets Chaos Engineering</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/when-prospect-theory-meets-chaos-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 08:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/when-prospect-theory-meets-chaos-engineering/</guid>
      <description>There is a connection between my research into behavioral models of information security and my Black Hat USA talk with Dr. Forsgren from last week regarding DevOps and the future of information security that might not be immediately obvious. However, it is a connection I believe is worth illuminating.
Adopting the “chaotic infosec” philosophy (the application of chaos engineering to information security) can influence those who build and secure systems to operate more like attackers – that is, to be more risk averse and to more quickly update their mental models given new inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Black Hat USA 2019 Business Hall</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:35:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2019/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisite plug that you should come see my talk with Dr. Nicole Forsgren at Black Hat next week (16:00 in South Pacific)!
What type of vendors are showing themselves off in the Business Hall? Are they mostly startups? Exactly like last year, 46% of the vendors in the Business Hall are startups backed by venture capital (VC) firms. Private companies represent only 13% of total vendors this year (vs. 17% last year), and there are far more acquired companies (&#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Darth Jar Jar: a Model for Infosec Innovation</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/darth-jar-jar-model-infosec-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 08:30:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/darth-jar-jar-model-infosec-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Despite its seeming absurdity and superficiality, the theory of Darth Jar Jar can serve as a poignant parable for security innovation. For those unfamiliar, the notion of a Darth Jar Jar springs from a meticulously researched fan theory from the Star Wars subreddit. While I do not wish to spoil the breathtaking beauty of the fleshed-out theory, the underlying legend is one of an ostensibly bumbling fool who, in reality, is an insidious puppet master full of cunning and strength.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reflections on the 2019 RSA Conference</title>
      <link>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/my-reflections-on-rsac-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 21:28:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swagitda.com/blog/posts/my-reflections-on-rsac-2019/</guid>
      <description>Artist’s rendition of how I felt by Thursday morning of the con
Reflecting on my existential crisis during RSAC, I tried to distill what exactly was so troublesome about the conference. The expo floor was less two separate halls, as per years prior, and more like Mordor, with a befouled sprawl connecting Minas Morgul and the Black Gate — but instead of orcs and Uruk-hai, vendors crammed the hallways that used to serve as open breathing space.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
