<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Market Analysis on Kelly Shortridge</title>
    <link>//swagitda.com/blog/tags/market-analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Market Analysis on Kelly Shortridge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:35:54 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="//swagitda.com/blog/tags/market-analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Black Hat USA 2019 Business Hall</title>
      <link>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2019 08:35:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2019/</guid>
      <description>Prerequisite plug that you should come see my talk with Dr. Nicole Forsgren at Black Hat next week (16:00 in South Pacific)!
What type of vendors are showing themselves off in the Business Hall? Are they mostly startups? Exactly like last year, 46% of the vendors in the Business Hall are startups backed by venture capital (VC) firms. Private companies represent only 13% of total vendors this year (vs. 17% last year), and there are far more acquired companies (&amp;ldquo;M&amp;amp;A&amp;rdquo; within the chart) this year (8% vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Reflections on the 2019 RSA Conference</title>
      <link>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/my-reflections-on-rsac-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 21:28:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/my-reflections-on-rsac-2019/</guid>
      <description>Artist’s rendition of how I felt by Thursday morning of the con
Reflecting on my existential crisis during RSAC, I tried to distill what exactly was so troublesome about the conference. The expo floor was less two separate halls, as per years prior, and more like Mordor, with a befouled sprawl connecting Minas Morgul and the Black Gate — but instead of orcs and Uruk-hai, vendors crammed the hallways that used to serve as open breathing space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>InfoSec Startup Buzzword Bingo: 2019 Edition</title>
      <link>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/infosec-buzzword-bingo-2019-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 16:57:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/infosec-buzzword-bingo-2019-edition/</guid>
      <description>This is the third edition of my Infosec Buzzword Bingo, just in time for 2019’s RSA Conference (RSAC). Rather than relying on my keenly tuned snake oil spidey senses to generate the words populating the bingo card, I took a more data-driven approach this year.
I surveyed 100 companies’ websites[1], the vast majority of which are exhibiting at RSAC and possess VC funding. I did not include any of the large security vendors[2], who probably could populate their own bingo cards across their mastodonian websites.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the 2019 RSA Innovation Sandbox Finalists</title>
      <link>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2019-rsa-innovation-sandbox-finalists/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 19:02:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-2019-rsa-innovation-sandbox-finalists/</guid>
      <description>This year’s nominees for the 2019 edition of the RSA Conference’s Innovation Sandbox were announced this morning. As I’m wont to do, I wanted to explore the funding side of these ten startups.
Total Funding Raised &amp;amp; the Latest Stage for each 2019 RSA Innovation Sandbox Finalist ($USD millions)
The median funding raised by all ten startups is $10.5 million (mean of $10.3 million), which makes sense for an early stage-flavored competition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing the Black Hat USA 2018 Business Hall</title>
      <link>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2018 18:40:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//swagitda.com/blog/posts/analyzing-blackhatusa-business-hall-2018/</guid>
      <description>What type of vendors are showing themselves off in the Business Hall? Are they mostly startups? Not quite “mostly,” but 46% of vendors in the hall are indeed VC-backed companies at varying stages of maturity. Privately held companies are a non-trivial segment at 17%, and there are 30 Private Equity-owned companies making up 12% of the hall. There are also 12 companies who are acquisitions, primarily those who were acquired within the past year; booths require being booked far in advance, leaving insufficient time to be assimilated into their acquiror’s booth (if so desired).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>